A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Housing Interests, Series J FA319
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Forest Hill Property
  - Forest Hill Property - Park Footbridge, 1938-1946 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    Maps, blueprints, cost estimates; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. praise of Work Progress Administration (WPA); tablet dedication. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wilbur Watson.
    127P3
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park, 1938-1951 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    A. D. Taylor's study; plans to develop estate as public park. Cleveland Heights City Council approval of preliminary plan. Use of work relief money in development project. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s desire note to have name connected with park or lake; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pleasure at development plans. Study of trees in park; fire at Guest Lodge; death of A. D. Taylor. Correspondents include F. C. Cain, F. Staley, L. Sleinkofer, J. Schlitz, A. D. Taylor, Charles Carran, A. L. Chipman, A. B. Williams, Robert W. Gumbel, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Clippings, 1937-1941 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Letters of Appreciation, 1939-1948 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Appraisals, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    1940 appraisal of land deed to East Cleveland by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Dugway Brook Culvert, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Covering brook property with culvert; agreement to cover only East Cleveland portion; deed to property, to get Work Progress Administration (WPA) funds for work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agrees to provide sponsor's share of construction costs.
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Offer & Deeds, 1937-1942 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Assessed valuation; payment of taxes; quitclaim deed of culvert and sewer premises. Agreement by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Cities of Cleveland Heights and East Cleveland for establishment of Forest Hill Park; costs of program. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Charles O. Heydt, Frank Staley, J. C. Jones, Charles Carran, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Forest Hill Property - Gift of Land for Park - Letter Offering Land; Resolutions, 1937-1942 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Offer of land; acceptance by East Cleveland City Commission and City Council of Cleveland Heights; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letter of thanks for resolution.
  - Forest Hill Property - Statements of Cost, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Received from Charles O. Heydt; expenditures; cost of properties purchased from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; monthly summary reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    127T
  - Forest Hill Property - "Forest Hill Park: A Report on the Proposed Landscape Development" - Laurance S. Rockefeller Copy, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 0055A)
  - Forest Hill Property - "Forest Hill Park: A Report on the Proposed Landscape Development" - Nelson A. Rockefeller Copy, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 0055B)
  - Forest Hill Property - "Forest Hill Park: A Report on the Proposed Landscape Development", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 0055C)
  - Forest Hill Property - Use of Property Donated for Park, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    Requests for use of park land for non-park purposes; reverter clause in 1897 deed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    127P4
  - Forest Hill Property - A. D. Taylor Report, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Presentation volumes of Nelson A. Rockefeller and Laurance A. Rockefeller's bound copies of Taylor report.
  - Forest Hill Property - Forest Hill - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 58)
    Notebook containing photographs of types of homes in Forest Hill.
    General note
    Removed to photo collection.
  - Forest Hill Property - Publicity - McCann-Erickson Company, 1929-1936 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    Publication of booklet describing Forest Hill; newspaper advertisements; publicity campaign; preparation of booklets, articles.
    127T4
  - Forest Hill Property - Publicity - Newspaper Clippings, 1928-1949 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Forest Hill Property - Publicity - Newspaper Clippings - Development Project, 1925-1932 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    From Cleveland newspapers; plans for sales and advertising campaigns. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. J. Thomas, Bruce Bliven, Frank Staley.
  - Forest Hill Property - Metropolitan Park District, 1918-1925 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    Activities of Metropolitan Park District, Cleveland Recreation Council. Desire of Park Board to acquire all or part of Forest Hill for park purposes. Correspondent include Williard S. Richardson, S. H. Holding, Charles O. Heydt, A. B. Smythe, Rowland Haynes.
    127.1
  - Forest Hill Property - Deming, R. B., 1918-1937 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    Cleveland architect with plans for developing Forest Hill unsuccessfully attempted to interest John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include B. R. Deming, Charles O. Heydt.
    127.1D
  - Forest Hill Property - Van Swearingen Correspondence, 1920-1937 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    Purchase and sale of real estate by Van Swearingen; assistance in plans for development of Forest Hill. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Betram Cutler, A. L. Boulware, A. O. Van Swearingen.
    127.1V
  - Forest Hill Property - Photographs of Forest Hill (Box 25, Folder 221)
    Photocopies of actual photographs.
  - Forest Hill Property - Photographs of Forest Hill (Box 25, Folder 222)
  - Forest Hill Property - Photographs of Forest Hill (Box 25, Folder 223)
  - Forest Hill Property - Photographs of Forest Hill (Box 25, Folder 224)
  - Forest Hill Property - Photographs of Forest Hill (Box 25, Folder 225)
  - Forest Hill (Box 26, Folder 226)
    Information about Forest Hill residential development, Cleveland, Ohio. Includes maps, plans, and photographs.
  - Forest Hill Homes, Abeyton Realty Corporation, Cleveland Heights, Ohio (Box 26, Folder 227)
    Photographs, floor plans, and descriptions of Forest Hill Home Development.
- Harlem Apartments
  - Harlem Apartments - Five Blocks - Housing, 1926-1937 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    Cancellation of leases, regrading, condemnation by City; regrading, sale of rock, construction of Harlem River Houses. Correspondents include A. J. Thomas, Charles O. Heydt, R. C. Bruce.
    232
  - Harlem Apartments - Five Blocks - Purchase, 1926-1930 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    Purchase of land; reasons for purchase. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Harlem Apartments - Five Blocks - Purchase - Harnett Case, 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    Thomas Harnett's contention that he was entitled to a brokers fee. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, Thomas J. Hartnett.
  - Harlem Apartments - Five Blocks - Purchase - Consolidated Gas Company; United Electric Company, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    Confusion over billing.
  - Harlem Apartments - Four Blocks - Sale and Condemnation, 1930-1936 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    Negotiations with the City; attempts to sell property; condemnation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, Charles O. Heydt, F. LaGuardia.
  - Harlem Apartments - Four Blocks - Publicity, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Harlem Apartments - Three Lots, West 150th Street - Playround, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    Purchase; gift to City. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., R. Moses.
    232.1
- Housing
  - City and Suburban Homes Company, 1896-1918 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. underwrote a portion of stock of new company; subsequently withdrew. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George D. Rogers.
    179
  - Metropolitan Problems, Studies, Committees, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    Reports on urban renewal; Laurance S. Rockefeller interest in New York Foundation for the renewal of urban housing - "Conservation, Rehabilitation and Renewal Foundation." Correspondents include W. T. Lindquist, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Metropolitan Problems, Studies, Committees - Charles Center, Baltimore, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    David Rockefeller interest in urban renewal in Baltimore; no investment made.
  - Housing - General, 1955-1961 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    Appeals to support low-cost housing projects declined. Data and information re low-cost housing, discrimination problems. Correspondents include Kenneth Chorley, Arthur Woods, Charles O. Heydt, Raymond B. Fosdick, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Thomas B. Appleget, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, W. T. Lindquist.
    179.1
  - Housing - General, 1955-1961 (Box 8, Folder 0075A)
  - Housing - General, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Housing - General, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 0076A)
  - Housing - General, 1950-1958 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Housing - General, 1950-1958 (Box 8, Folder 0077A)
  - Housing - General, 1948-1952 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Housing - General, 1948-1952 (Box 8, Folder 0078A)
  - Housing - General, 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    Appeals to support low-cost housing projects declined. Data and information re low-cost housing, discrimination problems. Correspondents include Kenneth Chorley, Arthur Woods, Charles O. Heydt, Raymond B. Fosdick, Dana S. Creel, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas B. Appleget, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, W. T. Lindquist.
  - Housing - General, 1935-1946 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Housing - General, 1914-1933 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Housing - General, 1923-1927 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Housing - General - National Housing Conference, 1927-1936 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Housing - Miscellaneous Data, 1929-1939 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    Reports and pamphlets.
  - Housing - Miscellaneous Data, 1911-1933 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Housing - Miscellaneous Data, 1928-1942 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Rockefeller Foundation, 1930-1942 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    Surveys on housing needs; proposed Housing Research Institute. Correspondents include Grosvenor Atterbury, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Task Force - Middle Income Housing, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    Lindquist served on task force organized to advise Governor Rockefeller on housing; drafting housing program; comments on proposals. Correspondents include W. T. Lindquist.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Task Force - Middle Income Housing, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Task Force - Middle Income Housing, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Task Force - Middle Income Housing, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - East Side Housing - Housing Association of New York, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    Proposals for the development of the area; appeals. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Raymond B. Fosdick, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, A. J. Thomas, H. Bruere, A. E. Smith.
    179.1A
  - East Side Housing - Housing Association of New York, 1928-1931 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    Plans for small slum clearance program to provide staff housing for Rockefeller Institute, Memorial Hospital and other centers; political opposition. Failure to get city cooperation in condemnation proceedings. Purchase of property Memorial Hospital. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, W. T. Lindquist, R. Moses.
    179.2
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1950-1955 (Box 10, Folder 0094A)
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1955-1956 (Box 10, Folder 0095A)
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - East 68th-69th Street Development, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 0096A)
- City Housing Corporation
  - City Housing Corporation, 1925-1955 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. subscribed to stock, assumed mortgages in construction of Sunnyside Gardens in Long Island City. 1936-1939 financial statements; plans for development of Rayburn; mortgage strike among tenants; notices of meetings. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Kenneth Chorley, Arthur Woods, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, Joh D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. M. Bing.
    179.3
  - City Housing Corporation - Col. Woods Correspondence, 1923-1956 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    A. M. Bing's housing scheme; Rockefeller office investigation of scheme. Construction progress of Sunnyvale Gardens; need for additional capital. Purchase of New Jersey land; construction of Radburn, with loan from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Financial difficulties. Correspondents include Arthur Woods, Kenneth Chorley, Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. M. Bing, H. Hoover, Beardsley Ruml.
    179.31
  - City Housing Corporation - Col. Woods Correspondence, 1926-1931 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - City Housing Corporation - Radburn Development, 1928-1933 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    Mortgage; moratoria on payments; release of secured notes in exchange for unsecured. Efforts to avert foreclosures and to dispose of property. 1945 refinancing; 1946 resumption of holdings; payments on notes, liquidation. Correspondents include A. M. Bing, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - City Housing Corporation - Radburn Development, 1928-1954 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - City Housing Corporation - Radburn Development, 1933-1942 (Box 11, Folder 102)
- American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    Organized to give advice on conservation of housing; David Rockefeller contributed to tax-exemption study; Lindquist was director until 1961. correspondents include David Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel, W. T. Lindquist.
    179.4
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 0103A)
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods, 1954-1959 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods, 1954-1959 (Box 11, Folder 0104A)
  - American Council to Improve Our Neighborhoods - Printed Material, 1956-1962 (Box 11, Folder 105)
- Thomas Garden Apartments
  - Thomas Garden Apartments, 1925-1930 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    Evolution of plan; financial arrangements; construction. Administration problems; violations; depression difficulties. Purchase of tenant equities; foreclosures; sale. Memo re files sent to Pocantico Hills. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, Arthur Woods, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Staley, A. J. Thomas.
  - Thomas Garden Apartments, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Publicity - Clippings, 1926-1932 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Record Book, 1927-1930 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    Important company papers; legal papers; prospecti, forms.
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Tenants, 1927-1935 (Box 12, Folder 110)
    Correspondence with tenants; arrears; rental arrangements. Complaints. Correspondents include Frank Staley, Charles O. Heydt, O. A. Robertson.
    179.41
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Tenants, 1928-1931 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Statements - Balances, 1928-1932 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    179.42A
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Organization, 1926-1940 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    Organization, meetings, dissolution. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Taxes, 1928-1931 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    Investigation of assessment; application for reduction; assessments.
    179.44
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Mortgage Foreclosure, 1935-1937 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    Foreclosure; Sale.
    179.48
  - Thomas Garden Apartments - Mortgage Foreclosure - Sale to Post Orchard Corporation, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    Contract; closing statement.
  - A. J. Thomas, 1924-1936 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    Thomas' plan for cooperative ownership of tenement housing; information about Thomas, his capabilities; relations with him. Correspondents included A. J. Thomas, Charles O. Heydt.
    179.5
- Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments, 1926-1941 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    Plans, choice of name for apartments, renting; medal to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from American Institute of Architects; tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Gift to R. Bruce. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, A. J. Thomas, R. C. Bruce, Frank Staley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    179.6
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Postcards, Pictures, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    Photographs of Paul Laurance Dunbar; correspondence re printing postcards.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also RAC Photograph Collection, Series 1005.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Descriptive Booklet, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    Two promotional brochures on P. Dunbar written by R. C. Bruce.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Purchase of Land, 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    Payments, title; legal problems; collection of rents.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Owners and Tenants Electric Company, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Tenants, 1928-1936 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    Collection of arrears; work on apartments; complaints, appeals and requests. Garnishment and dispossess proceedings. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, Frank Staley, Charles O. Heydt, R. C. Bruce.
    179.61
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Tenants, 1928-1935 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Record Book, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    Company papers - legal, property, forms, correspondence.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Incorporation - Organization, 1927-1937 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    Agreement among John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Empire Mortgage co., Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments. Financing; taxes; reduction in rents. Organization; dissolution, sale. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler.
    179.62
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Offer Empire Mortgage to PLD Apartments, 1927-1936 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    Deed, mortgage.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Preferred Stock Offer, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer to subscribe.
  - Dunbar National Bank, 1927-1930 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    Charter; construction, installation of equipment, hiring of personnel. Data on banking, banking conditions, depression; policy, administrative details, changes in by-laws. Liquidation; securing of jobs for old employees. Correspondents include A. J. Thomas, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, R. C. Bruce.
    179.63
  - Dunbar National Bank, 1930-1942 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Dunbar National Bank - 135th Street Branch, 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    Opening; reception. Administrative details.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Dunbar Safe Deposit Company, 1928-1933 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    Organization.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Charter, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Dunbar National Bank - Newspaper Clippings, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 0133A)
  - Dunbar National Bank - Loans to New Tenants, 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    Loans guaranteed by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Stockholders, 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    Organization; stock subscription. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to make up losses. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Bertram Cutler, Robert W. Gumbel, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Mr. Bruce's Stock, 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    Election of R. C. Bruce as a director; Bruce note to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to borrow enough to buy a qualifying amount of stock.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Directors, 1928-1939 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    Choice of directors; lists; oaths, elections. Transmission of minutes. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Robert W. Gumbel, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Dunbar National Bank - Liquidation, 1937-1947 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    Proposed liquidation; letters advising depositors and shareholders; disposition of assets. Fees; liquidation dividend. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Bertram Cutler.
    179.631
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Miscellaneous Material, 1927-1937 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    Rental values; payment plans; leases. Amortization schedules; analyses of vacancies; cubic content.
    179.66
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Newspaper Articles - Publicity, 1925-1937 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    179.68
  - R. C. Bruce - Application for Position, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    Recommendations; resume. Policy recommendations. Correspondents include R. C. Bruce, Charles O. Heydt, O. A. Robertson.
    179.610
  - R. C. Bruce - Personal, 1928-1940 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    Dinner with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; Bruce memoranda; Bruce's arrears as tenant; release from duties; appeals for aid. Mrs. Bruce's relation to other organizations; her damage suit. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, C. B. Bruce, R. C. Bruce, Frank Staley.
  - R. C. Bruce - Suit - November 1929, 1927-1930 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    Mrs. Harriet Shadd Butcher against R. C. Bruce.
  - R. C. Bruce - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 144)
    179.617
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Sale and Foreclosure, 1935-1936 (Box 16, Folder 145)
    Decision to sell; attempted sales, offers to buy. City condemnation; sale to 320 E. 73rd St. Corporation. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise, Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Frank Staley, R. C. Bruce.
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Sale and Foreclosure, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 146)
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Sale and Foreclosure, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Sale to New York City Housing Authority, 1935-1937 (Box 16, Folder 148)
    Unsuccessful negotiations. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, Frank Staley.
    179.617A
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Sale to 320 E. 73rd St. Corporation, 1937-1943 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    Contract; payments (subject to mortgage). Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Phillip Keebler, Frank Staley, Clark T. Chambers.
    179.617B
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Gift of 320 E. 73rd Stock, 1941-1945 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    Gift of 320 E. 73rd St. Corporation stock from C. T. Chambers to New York Society of the Methodist-Episcopal Church. Sale subject to mortgage; satisfaction of mortgage. Correspondents include Phillip Keebler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    179.617B1
  - Paul Laurance Dunbar Apartments - Legal Papers - Confirmed Papers, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    1942 agreement between C. T. Chambers, Inc. and 320 E. 73rd St. Corp. Assignment of stock to Methodist-Episcopal Church; modification of mortgage, 1942. 1942 John D. Rockefeller, Jr. agreement with Methodist-Episcopal Church, C. T. Chambers, and 320 E. 73rd St. and Chase National Bank.
- New York State and New York City Housing
  - New York State Housing Legislation, 1926-1947 (Box 17, Folder 152)
    Copies of laws; Charles O. Heydt's advice. Information, reports, clippings, data; relations of office to Governor's Advisory Committee on Housing. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Kenneth Chorley.
    179.7